Okay guys, let's speak about the last topic of this journey.
What is important?
What do you need to check the box when it comes to influencer launch, the actual calendar?
And I will also touch and go a little bit more into the depth, why building relationship
with this winning and high performing influencers will benefit you and the brand.
All right, first things first, preparation, when it comes to launching, this is the most
important things you have to check the box, all right?
And also with that being said, don't think too much about anything else outside these
dots that I've been putting here for you.
First of all, you will get an influencer content video from the influencer that you agreed
on that you have closed the contract for or with.
And these videos, these videos is around one to two minutes long, most of the times.
If it's a good influencer, actually, they will give you a video that is longer than two
minutes.
So when you speak to the influencer, you can tell them there is no limits for the length
of the video because when you're working with these people, the longer the video, the
more incredible, probably it will be.
That's just facts.
So from this video that they will public in the story that we already have spoken about,
you will try to create together with your editor or yourself five to ten variants.
How do we do this?
So as you know, a video, if it starts here, and then this is two minutes, and it ends here,
what you will try to do, it's just change the hook from the video using the same video.
You don't ask for more clips or more hooks from the influencer.
You just edit it yourself because that's the easiest way if you try to get more content
out of the influencer, they will try to charge you way more, and that's not worth it.
But it's worth, however, is to use the same content and you by your marketing skills, you
just edit different hooks.
So for example, this part of the video, make a new hook from the total video, and then you
take this part of the video, also make a hook, and this part of the video also make a hook.
As I said, five to ten variants, you can edit it, however you want, but at least change
the hook with a different part of the video, alright?
Why?
As an any marketing and performance marketer expert, we want to try, we want to diversify the
risk when we launch these units and we want to identify which is the winning hook, which
I also write here, what is the winning hook from this influencer, which will help you once
you launch a second collaboration from this influencer, alright?
Amazing.
Photos for statics, photos for static ads, super good, this is incredible.
So there's two ways you can request this.
One is you just ask for the picture or photo, holding the product, smiling with the product,
whatever, or you take screenshots from this, the same video, from this video, you, you take
screenshots from the, from here or from this part of the video, whatever, you, you, you, you
will know the best.
And try to make three, five screenshots and then publish them as content rights as well.
No, I'm sorry, with ads as well.
And this should not be a problem from doing this because you purchased the rights to using
this content that you received.
That's why we will try to squeeze everything out of it ourselves with our own edits, with
our own screenshots instead of requesting more content from them, alright?
That's a trick or a hack that you can do.
Then the next thing, set that line on the calendar.
If you, if we agree to get two weeks content rights, if you are your own media buyer or if
you have an media buyer, you need to put this on the calendar and you can also put it as
a turn off the specific date on the ad account because this is also something that we've experienced
many times that can ruin the relationship.
It can also become fees for, for example, forgetting about the deadline, they will charge
you double, they will charge you like a penalty fee and this is things that you don't want.
And most of the, and the most important part is that you don't want to ruin a relationship
with a good influencer because you will just lose the trust from your end as a brand.
Now every green content, super important, never launch, let's say here.
So one influencer, right, please try to launch this together with at least three other formats
of content.
So as you can see, right, you can do some just a static, not from the influencer but just
more other ads and what else animations.
So the more content you have launching the same day, all right, here, same day, the better.
Why is this important because in sales, more times than not, the actual sales doesn't come
from the first contact point for the consumer.
So there is a law here.
The law says that average or all the sales comes on the third contact point, which means
that a lot of people might see the ad with the influencer, they like it, they even would
trust to buy from it and they don't because something comes up, right, but the more content
you get together with the influencer content, you would see way more results, way more spike
and boosting from the momentum of getting this influencer out there on your ad account.
You have to have way more every green content to make these better results, a better outcome
and to also have a better longevity from the, from the total ad account, from the total
campaign of this influencer, super important, three influencers, I have a rule.
So what is the rule?
I almost never launched an influencer alone the same week.
So three influencers on the same week.
This creates massive results, massive results because you are picking super extraordinary influencers
and when you are launching these on the same week, for example, with one day next to each
other or maybe two day next to each other, you will create a compound effect because this
might be influencers that are very recognizable for some people and you will just create a way
higher outcome, a way stronger outcome if you do it next to each other.
Don't wait, don't launch one influencer one week, the second, the next week and the third
week, it's too long, you have to wait, you have to launch this in the same week, one two days
next to each other, never forget about that, super good.
This is the most important stuff, you don't have to overthink, there is not much more things
that you have to think about, keep it simple guys and do it right to the basic rights.
If you do the basic rights, you will get outstanding results, relationship, let's jump to their relationship.
Alright guys, for a lot of you, if you have been doing business for at least three years
or more, three to ten years, I think for every year that you have been succeeding or keep
doing your business as an entrepreneur, you will actually see this yourself, how important
relationship or the ability to create relationship is.
We're speaking about your employees, your partners, influencers, suppliers, whatever.
Once you have a relationship, it creates a niche, it creates leverage and it creates
long-term business, sustainable business.
If you lack relationships, you're lacking so much, my friends, so this rule and this, what
I'm telling you, will amplify and amplify to any department, not only influencers, but
I will speak about why this is important for influencers.
First of all, these kind of influencers are extremely selective, alright, and they have a lot
of brands speaking to them and they have probably a lot of great opportunities with how can
I explain this easier.
You have to understand that they might think that they don't need you.
This is the reason, so they don't need you, alright, so you are just a new brand, a new
collaboration, etc.
But when you have a relationship, then they will want to need you.
It's different, the outcome, everything becomes different and that's why it becomes a long-term
profit because once you find a good influencer, you want to keep working with this influencer
until it's no longer like a positive ROI.
It's like finding a creator, if you guys are already owners of Ecom owners, you know, but once
you find a good creator, right, and you should have a relationship with the creator as well,
right, but you don't want the creator to just run away to multiple hundreds of brands and
then just give you what, one percent of focus, one percent of dedication, you want dedication,
you want focus, you want maybe loyalty.
So this is the reason, especially with high-performing macro influencers, extremely important.
Because the first-time profit is not the real profit, the real profit comes when they start
to continue working with you because the more the work with you, the better the content
gets, and the more credibility they will generate to your product and your brand because the perception
of the audience will be like this person really loves and lives with this product.
So that's why.
And this is the feeling you want to transmit to the public, to the audience, to the consumer.
Priority, what does it mean?
If you don't have a relationship with this influencer, if you are very transactional, then they
will might just keep you for a month or two months or three months.
Why?
Because they have a better deal with higher payments, a bigger company, whatever, a product
that they like maybe more, so and then you will not have any leverage to close a new deal
with this influencer and you don't want that because it's extremely hard to find this influencer.
So you don't want to get them and then just lose them, you want to get them and then grow
with them.
So priority is extremely important that they will give you and the way is by communicating
a lot, have like a weekly call with them, weekly call, do a video call, speak about hey look,
the campaign went amazing.
This was really good.
Tell me what is your followers saying, always ask followers, ask their followers.
I will teach you something here.
These kind of influencers, I'm not saying every influencer, absolutely not, but this high
performing influencers that can generate millions, they are extremely close with their audiences.
They are speaking on DMs every fucking day.
They are asking everything to their audiences, hey did you like the product, hey, if any complaint,
they get any complaint, you will hear about it and they will lack trust on you if there's
too much complaints because they understand the value of their audience.
So they are treating their audience as the highest priority, way more prioritized than
you by the way.
So by having weekly calls as the influencer, what their audience is saying about their product
experience, what how can we improve as a brand?
Let's speak about this, let's have fun, let's, you know, if the influencer has kids, ask
about the kids, be a friend, alright, make a friend.
This is what they love and once they feel that you have a relationship with them, then they
will give you so much more value.
They will give you sometimes like they will public about the brand without even knowing, without
even charging and they will tell you so much great insights about your brand that comes
from their audience for example.
So this is just amazing benefits once you have a relationship with them, contract adjustments.
Let me tell you something.
When you are working long term, I will actually put these, I will put this here.
When you are working long term with an influencer, so many things change, sales change, ideas on
content change, maybe the country you are selling it change, there is so many variables that
will change, alright, marketing fatigue, market share, competition, whatever, you name it.
There are so many things that will change and the contract that you write with them might
need to have adjusted, alright.
For example, in my own experience, we did from FlatFee, this was wrongly spelled, FlatFee
is the most normal, right?
They charge you one time fee, one flat fee for a story, etc.
For a lot of influencers actually, it is way better to get through revenue percentage for
example, or like commission, sometimes 100% commission or sometimes 20% commission together
with a flat fee, whatever, whatever fits the relationship the best for the health and
the growth of the brand, and also for the benefit of the influencer, there is never like
a one solution here, the best solution is a customized solution, it's a customized
collaboration and agreement, but influencers are not the best at doing business and deals,
right?
So they will be very close to speak about this, because they will be afraid, they will
think that you will be trying to take advantage.
So this is also the benefit of having a relationship, if you don't have a relationship, forget
about adjusting the contract, they will just believe that you want to take advantage.
But the truth is, the best or and the benefit for yourself or the brand for them might be
to customize the agreement, so you can do more collaborations.
And the reason a commission is way better, for example, is because, yeah, let's speak about
hyperflops, one of the best influencers did one collab a month with us, for example,
and we paid like 5k, all right?
And yeah, that was basically her profit, 5k was her earnings, and that's so standardized,
the whole influencer brand in collaboration about doing one collab, but then we started
to see that 5k over like 6 months period, it was starting to not be like super break even.
So what we did is we changed it to commission.
So what she started to do, we did 100% commission deal.
So instead of doing one collab a month, she mentioned, she mentioned happy flops on a daily
basis, but on a very natural way.
So it was not like a super fabricated video that we also used for content, et cetera, no.
She would just, if she was wearing happy flops in the morning and she was accidentally filming
it, she would just put the link in the stories, or she would just make let's say 15 collabs
in a month because of the 100 commission.
And she started to earn like 15 to 25k in commissions, right?
And we were having massive sales.
So and this was after 6 months.
So this is what I mean.
You don't need to be stuck in one like narrative in believing that, yeah, this is just one
time fee, this is a flat fee.
They don't want to hear you speaking about commission, they are afraid, et cetera, because
there is no relationship.
Why would it trust you?
Because you are just, as they say, in the world for Wall Street, she's just a salesman.
But the truth is, there is so many opportunities to work and methods to work with influencers,
but you can only do this and explore this if you have a relationship with them, right?
And you will have and you will need to adjust the contract over time, 100%.
High quality content.
Do you think that when a brand sent over a product, only email communication and then sending
a brief, et cetera, do you think that the influencer will give the best out of it, will make
the best content for this brand?
The answer is no.
The truth is that they will just try to do the best.
But once you have a relationship, they will want to make you proud because you have a relationship
as a bond.
So the expectations becomes completely different.
So the content that you will receive comparing to the other brands, you cannot even compare.
Because they will feel way more engaged with you.
They will put more effort.
They will go what?
The extra mile for you.
This is the benefit of relationships.
And then the best creating a business asset.
Listen guys, influencers, once you find a high performing influencers that can generate millions,
this is just a business asset.
It's like a source of income and never forget about that.
I've made so much more business from having relationships with so many influencers, not
only with one brand, with so many multiple brands of my own.
And I've helped other brands because this is an asset.
This is a business asset.
Never forget about that.
This is how you should think as a business man.
And that's why I also should create the best kind of relationship with these people.
Because it is a business asset.
And if you're an entrepreneur, it will be important for any project or any idea in the
future.
Alright guys, thank you very much, I hope they enjoyed all the full course and I wish you
the best.
I will also mention for brands that are already established that would like mentorship or further
more support from me or team.
Just reach out, we might qualify you to help you and see how more value we can add to you.
Great rest of your day and hope to see you one day.